[{"question":"Adder can be obtained by using an op-amp in","answers":{"a":"Inverting mode","b":"Non inverting mode","c":"Both modes","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"Which of the following is linear circuit?","answers":{"a":"Schmitt trigger","b":"Zero crossing detector","c":"Summing amplifier","d":"Voltage follower"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"An amplifier which multiplies each input by a factor and then adds all these values together called","answers":{"a":"Summing amplifier","b":"Scaling amplifier","c":"Averaging amplifier","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"Positive feedback is not used in Op-Amp mathematical operations because","answers":{"a":"It will lead the circuit to saturation","b":"It provides low voltage gain","c":"It makes the circuit prone to noise","d":"It heats up the circuit"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"The feedback resistance used in mathematical operations of Op-Amp is generally connected between","answers":{"a":"Non-inverting terminal and output terminal","b":"Inverting and output terminal","c":"Inverting and non-inverting terminal","d":"Positive saturation supply and inverting terminal"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"In which of the following are operational amplifiers (op-amps) used?","answers":{"a":"Oscillators","b":"Filters","c":"Instrumentation circuits","d":"All of the above"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"An inverting amplifier has Rf=2MΩ and R1=2KΩ. Its scale factor is","answers":{"a":"1000","b":"-1000","c":"10\u207B\u00B3","d":"-10\u207B\u00B3"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"What is the level of the current through the amplifier input(s) to ground in an op-amp?","answers":{"a":"Virtually zero","b":"1.7 mA","c":"2.8 mA","d":"3.3 mA"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"A summing amplifier can be used as","answers":{"a":"Averaging amplifier","b":"Subtractor","c":"Voltage follower","d":"Both A and B"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"The maximum frequency at which an op-amp may operate depends on the ________.","answers":{"a":"Bandwidth (BW)","b":"Slew rate (SR)","c":"Unity-gain bandwidth","d":"All of the above"},"correctAnswer":"d"}]
